NTANDO MACHAEA

66,14th Avenue, Gonubie, East London· 074 696 7412 **Ntandomap17@gmail.com· Ntando Machaea (LinkedIn)·**

I am a motivated young man with 3 years of programming in C# and 1 year with python. I am seeking an IT role in the company where I can be able to contribute my ideas and be mentored towards a successful career.

EXPERIENCE

DECEMBER 2019 – FEBRUARY 2020 BARTENDER, NEWS CAFÉ

Served bar and restaurant patrons ordered drinks, including beer, wine, and liquors. Kept bar area clean, safe, and well-stocked throughout each working shift.

MARCH 2023 - JUNE 2023

STUDENT ASSISTANT, NELSON MANDELA UNIVERSITY

Ensured the security on the examination room before, during and after the exam. Preventing possible candidate malpractice.

JULY 2023-OCTOBER 2023

L1 SUPPORT ANALYST, CONSTRUCT EDUCATION

Talked to clients and Canvas users to determine the nature of the issues they are experiencing, troubleshooting the issue on my end to see if I can replicate it. Advising clients on possible solutions and escalate the case if needed.

EDUCATION

MARCH 2021 - NOVEMBER 2023

DIPLOMA IT: SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT, NELSON MANDELA UNIVERSITY

Received the student merit award for two years in a row. Achieved 76% academic average on my first year and a 75,75% average in my second year of study.

JANUARY 2020 - NOVEMBER 2020

MATRIC, BYLETTS COMBINED SCHOOL

Achieved an admission to a bachelor's degree with two distinctions and an academic average of 69%.

UNIVERSITY PROJECTS

2022

PROPERTY AND RENTAL MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

- C# (Windows forms) and Microsoft SQL Server (Database)
- Enabled Tenants to register a new lease or terminate current one, View available properties. Agent was able to accept/decline lease extensions or new leases. Admin was able to accept new agents, Tenants as well as add new properties to the database.

2023

PRIMARY HEALTHCARE SYSTEM

- C# (ASP.net core 6.0 (LTC), MVC5, MS SQL Server.
- Enable patients to book and attend appointments at their healthcare facility.
 Counsellors, Nurses, and Doctors will be able to manage and update patient medical records.
- Repository link: https://github.com/Thato1708/eNompilo-PHC-System/tree/master

ADDITIONAL

- Technical skills: C#, python, html/CSS, JavaScript, MS SQL Server.
- Languages: English, isiXhosa, isiZulu, Sesotho
- Awards: Student Merit Award (2021 & 2022)

REFERENCES

- Miss Florida Mapoloba (Mentor): 072 152 1645
- Ms Khanyisile Libazi (Junior floor manager News Café): 071 804 3941
- Mr. Vuyolwethu Mdunyelwa (Lecturer): (+27) 41 504 1875
- Ms Hlela Bunn (Friend): 082 485 4807
- Ms Gugulethu Nombewu (Supervisor, Construct Education): 083 992 9782
- Ms Liesel Vincent (Manager, Nelson Mandela University): (+27) 41 504 2763